LI-TIEN OU

oulitien.com

litien@uw.edu 206.434.1486

Strong background in User-Centered Design process, interaction design, and information architecture. Strive to create intuitive and beautiful user experiences from concept to implementation.

3 year hands-on experience in web design & front-end development.

2 year experience in User Centered Design.

1 year working experience in product management & marketing.

PMP (project management professional) certificate.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UW

UX Designer, Seattle, WA

10/2014 - 07/2015

- Took ownership of LearnTogether, a learning platform design for corporate professional training and successfully shipped the v1 product to the major client Costco.
- · Gathered requirements from clients and conducted focus group to discover user needs.
- Helped define MVP and product features; built interactive Axure prototypes for demonstration.
- Designed adaptive layouts to maintain a consistent user experience across the product.
- · Delivered high quality design docs: sitemap, user flow, wireframes, mockups, specifications.
- Took charge of front-end development using tools including HTML, CSS, Less, Bootstrap.

Trend Micro 06/2014 - 09/2014

Ul Design Intern, Taipei, Taiwan

- Supported in the design of "Move Client" feature for OfficeScan: analyzed 4 case scenarios, strategized user flows and interactions, and delivered hi-fi Axure prototype.
- Took ownership of the internal UX guideline redesign to solve the inconsistency problem and increase the findability; got the proposal widely accepted across the UX team.

IBM

GBS Consultant Intern, Taipei, Taiwan

07/2013 - 08/2013

- Implemented data warehouse and ETL process to support selling and management services.
- · Wrote requirements specification and designed interfaces based on interview findings.

SYSTEX

08/2011 - 05/2012

Product & Marketing Specialist, Taipei, Taiwan

• Promote Guli - an stock calendar app: top free iOS App NO.8 in Taiwan's iTune store after hit the market 2 weeks; total download at least 30,000 times.

EDUCATION

M.S.

University of Washington, Seattle, WA

06/2015 M.S. in Information Management (MSIM), GPA: 3.74

• Coursework: User Centered Design, Interactive Design, Visual Communication Data Visualization, Project Management, Systems Analysis

B.B.A

National Sun Yat-Sen University (NSYSU), Kaohsiung, Taiwan

06/2011 B.B.A. in Information Management (IM), GPA: 3.85

AWARDS

Yoga Panda

01/0015

01/2015

UI/UX Designer - iOS App Design

2nd Place for Startup Weekend Euroseattle

PROJECTS

Transcend

UI/UX Designer - iOS App Design

01/2015 - 06/2015

UW Capstone Project sponsored by Prof. Katie Davis

- · A self-directed way to help take control of technology use and become app-enablement.
- · Led the UCD process, delivered personas, UI flow, prototype, and took charge of the visual design.

Babysteps

Prototype Engineer - Twitter App Prototyping

03/2013 - 06/2013 UW

UW Dub Research Group with Prof. Julie Kientz

 NSF-funded research focusing on designing technology to help detect, record, and track developmental milestone for children; defined IA and prototyped the Twitter app with python.

SKILLS

Design

Sketching
Wireframing
Visual Mockups
Illustrations
Icon Design
Interactive Prototyping
Responsive Web

Research

Contextual Inquiry Concept Mapping Affinity Diagram Personas / Scenarios Heuristic Evaluation Usability Testing

Architecture

Sitemap Flow Analysis Taxonomy XML

Programming

HTML / CSS JavaScript / jQuery MySQL / MSSQL Framer.js

Visualization

R & D3

Tool

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Axure Omnigraffle Sketch 3 MS Visio MS Project Github Less